<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maximilian Groh - digital and strategy geek with PhD</title>
    <description>Blogging about the digital economy, brand and strategic management</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 11:51:59 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 11:51:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coaching Technologies in Enhancing of Emotional Quotient of Manager</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the article: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://mgroh.eu/blog/leadership/what-is-leadership-coaching/&quot;&gt;What is Leadership Coaching?”&lt;/a&gt;, I explained the importance of training and guided the readers through the merits of allied technologies. Today I propose to consider the coaching technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coaching technology, as far as I can see, is a set of techniques, means and forms of effect on the personality of a future specialist which ensure the breadth of personal and professional development by means of interaction with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Coaching takes a holistic view of the individual: work, corporate values, personal needs and career development are made to work in synergy, not against one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;British Journal of Administrative Management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technological effectiveness of coaching consists, on the one hand, in a specific sequence of steps and procedures for dealing with a specialist and, on the other hand, inflexibility and variability of the techniques and means involved for solving of individual problems of a future manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any technology implies an algorithm of a certain process as well as management cycle of interrelated functions and operations which determinate achieving of stable results.
Designing and outlining of technology is an essential condition of its controllability and predetermines its spontaneity. Coaching program represents a set of actions aimed at implementing a coaching model in the process of professional training of a manager and adjusts the stages and periods required for the solution of the tasks at hand.
Different models are used in the coaching of enhancement of emotional quotient (EQ). Let’s take a closer look at the two models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first model is “who-what-how”. It includes three focus points which the trainee studies and elaborates together with the coach from session to session: “who” (the trainee, his objectives, values, needs, strengths, weaknesses, talents, limitations, manners of action, etc.); “what” (objectives of the trainee, tasks, dreams, what is needed, what is desired, what is given up and so on); and “how” (how to achieve, ways, possibilities, strategies, skills, technologies, techniques, methods and the like). Moreover, these focus points are shifted on a random basis, depending on the contents of the respective session: they can be elaborated in parallel, sequentially or in any order. The only thing that matters is that each focus point shall be elaborated to the full extent until everything is clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second model is “focus-cooperation-observation”. It is used, as a rule, after the establishment of contact between the coach and the trainee. At first, a particular topic is brought into focus. Then it is jointly elaborated during sessions (in operation) and what happens is analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method is suitable for helping athletes to overcome the plateau in competition form. Moreover, marketing strategies for enterprises are worked out in the same way.  The key idea is to monitor the results of every session carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general coaching technology reveals itself through coaching roles and functions when dealing with the trainee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Joint participation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach not only offers his knowledge but rather proposes a &lt;strong&gt;partnership&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;joint participation&lt;/strong&gt;. Knowledge is important too, but in coaching, it ranks second or even third. The priority is given to the ability of &lt;strong&gt;rendering support&lt;/strong&gt; in solving of problems which (a) have no standard and known in advance solutions, and (b) shall be solved by one’s efforts. The following may serve as examples of such tasks: working out of business strategy, establishing of the management team, settlement of conflicts and personnel management. Just working out of some management system which is, as a rule, proposed by traditional consultants, is nothing else but deadweight if a trainee fails to learn how to create and to use such systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Questions (&quot;What is interfering or preventing&quot;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the situation when a trainee knows how to act appropriately, but the expected result is not obtained, the coach comes to help, asking “what is interfering or hindering?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Encouraging of a trainee to search for alternatives and to select a solution (&quot;answer from the inside&quot;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even knowing how to solve a problem of a trainee, the coach seeks to make the trainee find a solution by himself. That is why the coach usually does not offer advice. Interaction happens by means of thought-provoking questions asked by the coach and joint analysis of the answers. Answering the questions, the trainee will gain more and more understanding of the task at hand and will be able to select the best solution. The coach may share his ideas with respect to the solution of the task at hand but will not insist on his point of view. The objective of the coach is to make it possible for the trainee to find a solution by himself by analyzing his own experience and assessment of the situation and, in such a manner, to contribute to his professional advancement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opportunities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach focuses on emerging opportunities rather than on action plans. Plans are necessary. &lt;strong&gt;They should be made&lt;/strong&gt;. However, not all situations unfold according to plans. It often happens that strict compliance with the plan hinders from taking of the emerging opportunities which have not been planned upfront. That is why one of the essential tasks of the coach is to keep drawing attention to the opportunities which are offered at every new stage of interaction meanwhile helping the trainee to make a plan for solving of the problem and to implement the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Skills&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach focuses on the skills and achievements of the trainee which enables the latter to see clearly the progress and to outline the path for further development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Process&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach helps the trainee to make the required changes in his life, views and beliefs by himself. The coach acts via the trainee and is responsible for the process of rendering assistance in solving the problem, while the trainee takes the actions planned during the session of coaching. In such a way, the coach helps and has the trainee advancing, instilling in the trainee independence and skills to find effective personal approaches to solving various problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;Capture&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach never insists on any alternative solution or advice. If the trainee does not perceive a solution or disagrees with it, then this solution is not appropriate for his reality. The coach should try to understand how the trainee perceives the reality and then to help him to widen the reality by asking precise, suggestive questions, to help the trainee to see what he has not seen before, being bound by the boundaries of his perception. Besides, the coach cannot see anything and everything that the trainee can see. The joint task in the process of coaching is to find together the most appropriate solution in every specific situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To summarize, it can be stated with certainty that:&lt;/strong&gt;
In terms of tactics, coaching technologies vary from educational sessions and seminars to auto-trainings and consulting. Gaining the achievements of the technologies of behavioural therapy, training and tutorship, coaching enables to perceive the philosophy of personal development with reliance on changing of attitudes of the leadership management nonviolently — from problem-focused interaction to dealing with the potentials and resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/coaching-technologies-enhancing-emotional-quotient-manager/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/coaching-technologies-enhancing-emotional-quotient-manager/</guid>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
        <category>coaching</category>
        
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Leadership Coaching?</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coaching process is based on the preconditions of human development and self-development. Intrinsically, every person is outstandingly talented and has enormous potential, which is not reached by the person to the full extent. Potentially, every subject contains answers to nearly all questions as well as possible solutions for evolving problems. Coach does not offer out-of-the-box advice or recommendation but helps a manager to find his solutions for the most relevant issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interactive communication, polylogue and discussion are the basic concepts of leadership coaching as a technology. The direct, perceptible and immediate result becomes an advantage of coaching in the process of improvement of emotional quotient (EQ). It is qualified as an intermediate result; however, it is crucial for training of specialists since it creates the motivational basis required for further professional and personal development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special requirements are imposed on the coach in the coaching process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;objectivation of issues dealt with during the process of interaction with a trainee;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;establishment of trust-based and partnership (equitable) relations which enable to remove barriers in the course of interaction and to facilitate the process of solving of problems which face a future specialist;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;experience and professional competence of the coach shall produce a synergetic effect on a manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the merits of the allied technologies which are borrowed from psychology and management, coaching determines positive development pathways in reliance on the attitude of personal fulfilment and self-fulfilment of a student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendations on the implementation of leadership coaching for the purpose of achieving of EQ of the future leader are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To define tasks and objectives (setting of benchmarks and priorities);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To look into the current situation (identifying of available resources and limitations); the coach tries to understand the current situation (problem), asking questions and listening attentively; the student analyzes the situation and his attitude towards it together with the coach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To identify internal and external obstacles to obtaining of the result: the coach tries to understand what prevents the manager from achieving of the objective and from helping him in realizing and analyzing of the obstacles; the manager reviews his internal and external obstacles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To work out and analyze the possibilities for clearing of the obstacles: the coach asks questions and uses other techniques provoking the manager into the finding of solutions and overcoming of constraints; the manager reviews the possibilities for clearing of the obstacles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To select a specific alternative scenario and to make a plan: the coach helps the manager in analyzing of the possibilities; the manager reviews the possibilities selects a specific alternative and makes an action plan. The coach and the manager agree on what exactly shall be done by the next meeting (by a specified date).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following components of professional training of a specialist are the main aspects for the implementation of coaching: objective, tasks, contents, technologies and result. During the introductory training session, besides the objective set by the coach, processes of self-planning and planning of the manager’s work are initiated, thus establishing the required level of involvement of the subject in the process of structuring of the coaching course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appraisal of the results is an essential element of control of success of the trainee exercised by the coach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/what-is-leadership-coaching/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/what-is-leadership-coaching/</guid>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
        <category>coaching</category>
        
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Improvement of Emotional Intelligence of Managers</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent times I am more and more frequently asked about the importance of improvement of the emotional intelligence of managers. I propose to gain insight into this aspect so that to find out whether it is essential or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A leader can be very destructive or very inspiring. It comes down to their level of emotional intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt; John Mackey, CEO of Whole Foods&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is stated in the research papers of D. Goleman that only 15% of the success of a manager is accounted for by his intelligence (IQ) while 85% fall on the emotional quotient (EQ)(Goleman, Daniel. &lt;em&gt;Emotional intelligence&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Bantam Books, 1995. Print.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following components of emotional intelligence or emotional quotient are distinguished in the papers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Managing of emotions&lt;/em&gt; (in line with the arising situations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self-awareness&lt;/em&gt;. It is a regular self-observation for recognition of emotions and moods as they happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self-motivating&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Empathy&lt;/em&gt;. Recognizing and understanding of emotions and expectations of another person as well as active involvement in his problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Managing of relationships&lt;/em&gt;. It is one of the measurements of social intelligence which is closely related to emotional intelligence (emotional quotient) since it applies to the domain of emotion management for maintaining and harmonizing of relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to many other notions, there are several approaches to what should be implied by emotional intelligence. The models developed by R. Bar-On(Reuven Bar-On, James D. A. Parker, Daniel Goleman. &lt;em&gt;Handbook of emotional intelligence: The theory and&lt;/em&gt;. [Place of publication not identified]: John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, 2000. Print.), D. Goleman(Goleman, Daniel. “Leadership that gets results.” &lt;em&gt;Harvard Business Review &lt;/em&gt;(01-MAR-2000). Print.), Mayer J. D. and P. Salovey(Salovey, Peter, Marc A. Brackett, and John D. Mayer. &lt;em&gt;Emotional intelligence: Key readings on the Mayer and Salovey model&lt;/em&gt;. Port Chester, N.Y. Dude Pub, 2004. Print.) are the best known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model of Mayer J. D. and P. Salovey includes only cognitive abilities associated with the processing of emotional information. Cognitive abilities are excluded from the model of R. Bar-On. Only personal characteristics are emphasized which, in my opinion, makes the notion of emotional intelligence somewhat metaphorical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is widely preferred to use the term “emotional quotient” (EQ), meaning the raw talents by emotional intelligence while emotional quotient should be understood as an ability to use the raw talents. EQ includes four groups of skills:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognizing of one's own emotions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognizing of other people's emotions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managing of one's own emotions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managing of other people's emotions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to various researches described by D. Goleman in his book “Emotional intelligence”, only from 4% to 25% of success in any activity is determined by intelligence. Based on the results of research carried out by him, 33% of successfulness any activity is determined by the intelligence quotient (IQ). As for the effectiveness of a manager, it depends on IQ only by 15%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does not mean at all that IQ of people who have obtained success is low. It is just that other factors begin to have an impact on success among people with high IQ. The totality of these abilities is called “emotional quotient”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, emotional quotient consists of the following separate emotional competences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self-understanding (self-awareness)&lt;/em&gt;: understanding of one's own internality, conceptions, resources and intuitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Emotional self-awareness&lt;/em&gt;: recognition of one's own emotions and their impact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accurate self-assessment&lt;/em&gt;: knowing one's strengths and limits (weaknesses).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self-respect&lt;/em&gt;: sense of one's self-worth and recognition of one's abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self-management&lt;/em&gt;: management of one's internality, impulses and resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self-control&lt;/em&gt;: keeping of disruptive emotions and impulses under control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transparency&lt;/em&gt;: maintaining of standards of honesty and integrity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Consciousness&lt;/em&gt;: assuming of personal responsibility for performing of something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adaptability&lt;/em&gt;: flexibility in adapting to external changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Orientation towards achievements&lt;/em&gt;: endeavors to improve and comply with the standards of excellence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Initiative&lt;/em&gt;: readiness to act as an opportunity is offered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social awareness&lt;/em&gt;: understanding of other people's emotions, needs and concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Empathy&lt;/em&gt;: sensing and understanding of other person's emotions and expectations as well as active involvement in his problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Organizational awareness&lt;/em&gt;: understanding of intra-group emotional flows as well as balance and relationships of power at the organizational level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social skills&lt;/em&gt;: guiding and motivating with a compelling vision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing of other people&lt;/em&gt;: sensing of other people's needs for development and bolstering of their abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leadership&lt;/em&gt;: ability to inspire individuals and to manage teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Influence&lt;/em&gt;: wielding of effective tactics for persuasion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communication&lt;/em&gt;: listening well and being persuasive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Change catalyst&lt;/em&gt;: initiating and managing of changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conflict management&lt;/em&gt;: clearing up of misunderstandings and resolving of disagreements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Building bonds&lt;/em&gt;: nurturing of instrumental relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Teamwork and collaboration&lt;/em&gt;: cooperation with other people for achievement of the common objective. Creation of cohesive team for pursuing of the collective objective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These abilities are grouped in four clusters (individual, individual abilities, interpersonal abilities and recognition), two of which include understanding and management of emotions (self-awareness and social awareness) and the other two differ in orientation towards the individual and communication partners (regulating, self-management and management of relationships):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self-awareness&lt;/em&gt; (emotional self-understanding, accurate self-assessment and self-confidence).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social awareness&lt;/em&gt; (empathy, orientation towards the needs of other people, organizational awareness).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regulating and self-management&lt;/em&gt; (self-control, trust, awareness, adaptability, orientation towards achievements and initiative).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Management of relationships&lt;/em&gt; (involvement of development of other people, influence, effective communication, conflict management, leadership, change catalyst, establishing of strategic relationships, teamwork and collaboration).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These capabilities enable a professional to establish relationships with people at the working place and to maintain these relationships effectively. It is the development of this social intelligence that drives a specialist to professional success.
Emotional abilities which comprise emotional intelligence are inherent to every person and can be developed all his life long. Their development affects the inner structures of personality, and that is why it is time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, working with employees aimed at the development of emotional intelligence lasts long enough. Finally, it gives stable and substantial results, allowing a professional to develop his personality and to comply with the highest standard of excellence in professional activities. The main sources of personnel development are associated in the management practice with the optimization of human resources. The latter depends directly on the management system and motivating of employees in the process of coaching and consulting. Coaching technologies ensuring of adjustment of development-oriented positions of a specialist and a future manager are at the heart of the specified procedures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work is carried out both at the level of an individual and the level of groups and teams. It enables companies to save millions of dollars (euro) a year owing to increasing of retention of trained personnel, interest and involvement of employees in professional activities, more effective communication with colleagues, reducing of conflicts at the working place, understanding and observance of subordination, reducing of an absence of personnel from work due to illness. Besides, it helps to establish cooperation between employees and partners at a more effective level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modelling of this process plays a significant role in defining the main ways of improvement of the emotional intelligence of a manager. Technologies of creation of competencies pertaining to emotional self-regulation include self-programming, self-management, exercises, trainings and self-observation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technologies of creation of competencies pertaining to perception and cognition of emotions of other people include business games, exercises and sharing. Technologies of creation of competencies pertaining to influence on emotions of other people include trainings and consulting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performance indicators of improvement of emotional intelligence can be defined in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with respect to awareness of one's feelings and emotions: intuition, optimism, commitment, flexibility, self-consciousness, perception, self-assessment, aspiration, empathy and self-observation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with respect to the management of one' feelings and emotions: observation skills, open-mindedness to new experience, involvement, the ability for development, emotional competence, positive thinking, listening well, responsibility, tolerance, self-control and achievement motivation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with respect to recognition of feelings and emotions of other people: cooperation, interpersonal skills, transparency to interaction, development of partner's interests, respect of other people's opinion, teamwork skills, assertiveness, leadership, trust, suggestion and anticipation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with respect to the management of feelings and emotions of other people: appropriate assessment of other people, ability to forecast the behaviour of others, empathy, transparency, appreciation of emotional interaction, positive resolution of conflicts, collaboration, identification and sympathy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Including of emotional intelligence in training programs or in enhancing the training of managers enables to identify the critical dominants in the professional development of personnel as well as to ensure the effectiveness of creating of drivers of management activity or improvement thereof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/improvement-emotional-intelligence-managers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/improvement-emotional-intelligence-managers/</guid>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
        <category>emotional intelligence</category>
        
        <category>EQ</category>
        
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Implications of the paradigm shifts in marketing</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A significant paradigm shift has occurred in marketing over the past three decades in which the focus of marketing practice has been away from the idea of exchanging a product or service with consumers to the idea of creating value and creating relationships with consumers (heth, J. N. &amp;amp; Uslay, C., 2007. Implications of the revised definition of marketing: From exchange to value creation. &lt;em&gt;American Marketing Association, 26(2), 302-307&lt;/em&gt;).  This paradigm shift has had several implications in marketing management practice for the marketing executive.  The days of creating overly generalized, one-way messages that informed consumers of why they needed to purchase a product or service have been replaced with a need to engage consumers in on-going interactions, and to be able to respond to changing cultural attitudes quickly (Penaloza, L. &amp;amp; Venkatesh, A., 2006. Furthermore evolving the new dominant logic of marketing: From services to the social construction of markets.&lt;em&gt;Marketing Theory, 6(3), 299-316&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this article is to examine the implications of the paradigm shifts in marketing for marketing management practice from the viewpoint of a marketing executive.  The ideas presented in this article are focused on the paradigm shift that has taken place in recent years, as well as what that paradigm shift has meant for creating and overseeing marketing management practice.  The importance of the ideas presented in this article is that insights are provided about the concerns that the marketing executive needs to hold with regards to managing marketing practices.  The underlying point for marketing executives is that marketing practice is no longer about a concern for the needs of a company.  Instead, marketing practice must focus on the needs of the consumer and creating a relationship with the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;paradigm-shift-and-implications-for-marketing-practice&quot;&gt;Paradigm Shift and Implications for Marketing Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a single, linear paradigm shift has not occurred within marketing over the past 30 years, the general trend that has occurred has been away from exchange marketing to value creation and relationship marketing (Sheth, J. N. &amp;amp; Uslay, C., 2007. Implications of the revised definition of marketing: From exchange to value creation. &lt;em&gt;American Marketing Association, 26(2), 302-307&lt;/em&gt;). Exchange marketing was focused on the idea that an exchange of a product or service needed to occur in order to solve a problem or enhance a situation (Penaloza, L. &amp;amp; Venkatesh, A., 2006. Furthermore evolving the new dominant logic of marketing: From services to the social construction of markets.&lt;em&gt;Marketing Theory, 6(3), 299-316&lt;/em&gt;)). In this way, marketing executives were concerned about creating a message to explain to consumers how a given product or service should be purchased because of the benefits that it could provide in order to solve a problem or enhance a situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paradigm shift that has occurred to value creation and relationship marketing in which a company focuses on the needs of the consumer provides a product or service to meet that need and then continues the relationship as a way to extending value creation over the long-term (Sheth, J. N. &amp;amp; Uslay, C., 2007. Implications of the revised definition of marketing: From exchange to value creation. &lt;em&gt;American Marketing Association, 26(2), 302-307&lt;/em&gt;). An essential part of this value creation paradigm in marketing is creation relationships and on-going interactions. Rather than selling a product or service to a consumer, companies engage with consumers in order to better understand that needs, not just at the current moment but over a period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies listen to the needs and desires of consumers (Penaloza, L. &amp;amp; Venkatesh, A., 2006. Furthermore evolving the new dominant logic of marketing: From services to the social construction of markets.&lt;em&gt;Marketing Theory, 6(3), 299-316&lt;/em&gt;).In this way, the consumer becomes part of the marketing decision-making process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the paradigm shift that has occurred in marketing, the question that arises is what is the implication of this paradigm shift for marketing executives. One of the implications of the paradigm shift is that marketing executives must view relationships with consumers and opportunities to create relationships with consumers as an essential part of the marketing process (Crowther, P. &amp;amp; Donland, L., 2011. Value-creation space: The role of events in a service-dominant marketing paradigm. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Marketing Management, 27, 1444-1463&lt;/em&gt;). For example, the use of the internet and social media cannot be viewed as a waste of resources or as a secondary marketing approach. Instead, marketing executives must use the internet and social media on a full-time basis in order to interact directly with consumers. However, merely using the internet and social media to interact with consumers is not enough. Marketing executives must use such interactions to understand the meanings that consumers assign to various interactions and contexts within their lives (Penaloza, L. &amp;amp; Venkatesh, A., 2006. Furthermore evolving the new dominant logic of marketing: From services to the social construction of markets.&lt;em&gt;Marketing Theory, 6(3), 299-316&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of understanding the meanings that consumers to assign to various interactions and products and services is the ability to better position a company and its products in the lives of consumers (Penaloza, L. &amp;amp; Venkatesh, A., 2006. Furthermore evolving the new dominant logic of marketing: From services to the social construction of markets.&lt;em&gt;Marketing Theory, 6(3), 299-316&lt;/em&gt;). A company that understands and appreciates the social and cultural values of its consumers and how they respond to broader social and cultural issues is able to become an active part of the lives of those consumers. In contrast, a company that is focused only on its values can easily be perceived as not caring about its targeted consumers. Even more, this type of company can alienate its targeted consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the current era of social media and the internet, consumers want to feel as though they are in control (Domegan, C. T., 2008. Social marketing: Implications for contemporary marketing practices classification scheme. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Business &amp;amp; Industrial Marketing, 23(2), 135-141&lt;/em&gt;).The paradigm shift to relationship marketing has been a response to the changing nature of consumers who are more willing to not purchase at all if a company is perceived not to be focused on their needs and their desires (Sheth, J. N. &amp;amp; Uslay, C., 2007. Implications of the revised definition of marketing: From exchange to value creation. &lt;em&gt;American Marketing Association, 26(2), 302-307&lt;/em&gt;).Marketing executives have to take the time to not only understand the needs and desires of their targeted consumers but also understand the larger social and cultural networks of their targeted consumers. Companies that target broad groups of consumers have to recognize how different sub-groups are likely to have different social and cultural networks. Marketing executives have to engage in marketing that is able to target these different social and cultural networks specifically.For example, marketing management might mean creating one type of marketing campaign for older adults while creating a different type of marketing campaign that is based on a current social and cultural issue or phenomenon for younger adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, companies have to consider how to become involved in the lives of consumers as they become involved in social and cultural issues. Marketing executives can no longer easily take a neutral ground in social issues if their targeted consumers are using social media and the internet to engage in social issues (Achrol, R. S. &amp;amp; Kotler, P., 2012. Frontiers of the marketing paradigm in the third millennium. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Academy of Marketing Sciences, 40, 35-52&lt;/em&gt;).In the past, marketing executives might have focused on neutral campaign messages and marketing approaches. In the current era of relationship marketing, marketing executives have to be able to make decisions about which social and cultural issues and phenomenon are of such importance to their consumers that become involved in those issues is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the shift in marketing paradigm has also meant that the practice of marketing management is not just about the initial message, but also the response from consumers to the message or the product or service that was purchased. Marketing executives must allow for the ability for consumers who complain about products or services to be contacted, particularly when complaints are voiced over social media(Achrol, R. S. &amp;amp; Kotler, P., 2012. Frontiers of the marketing paradigm in the third millennium. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Academy of Marketing Sciences, 40, 35-52&lt;/em&gt;). This is part of the larger process of creating relationships with consumers and allowing consumers to direct the message as opposed to the company being sole in charge of the marketing message (Domegan, C. T., 2008. Social marketing: Implications for contemporary marketing practices classification scheme. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Business &amp;amp; Industrial Marketing, 23(2), 135-141&lt;/em&gt;).Marketing executives must be concerned with the long-term concerns and attitudes of consumers toward their products or services. If consumers experience problems with their products or services, marketing must continue to understand the problems and then correct those problems before consumers are able to create negative perceptions of the company within their social networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, the entire process of marketing management has become both customer-focused and relationship-focused from the point of attempting to sell a product to the days and months after a product has been sold. Marketing executives must think beyond their concerns or the concerns of their companies. Instead, marketing executives must make the concerns and needs of consumers their priority in marketing. The goal should be to create value for the consumer and become part of the lives of consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past 30 years, a paradigm shift has occurred in marketing away from a focus on the exchange to a focus on creating relationships with consumers. This paradigm shift for marketing executives implies that marketing management has become more about relationship building than about the purchase of a good or service. Marketing executives must oversee the relationship management of the products and companies for which they are responsible. They must manage marketing processes in such a way as to make the consumer the focus of their efforts. The marketing executives that are unwilling to make the consumer the focus of the marketing process will likely find that it is difficult to attract consumers to their brands, and may even harm the long-term reputations of their companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/marketing-management/implications-paradigm-shifts-marketing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/marketing-management/implications-paradigm-shifts-marketing/</guid>
        
        <category>marketing management</category>
        
        <category>paradigm</category>
        
        
        <category>marketing-management</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts on leadership - People, System and Self</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leadership is an essential aspect of management as it determines the extent to which the organization is to achieve its objectives. There are, however, different considerations that a leader must make if he is to achieve his leadership goals. In my professional life as a manager and later as a director, I have encountered many challenges. In the process, I have learned many things about the right approaches to leadership. One of the biggest challenges is on how to influence the people that I lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have encountered ups and downs as my leadership style has yielded inconsistent results. At times, I may apply a particular leadership style and register high levels of success. At other times, when I apply the same style to a different group, the results are very different. As a leader, I am mandated to exert my influence over people who work in different regions. This has posed a significant challenge to me since those strategies that perfectly work in one region do not work in other regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These challenges have taught me several things about my leadership style. First, I have learned to vary my leadership styles according to the nature of the employees that I am dealing with. The strategies that I used with the non-professionals did not work at all with the professionals. For example, when dealing with ordinary employees who had no specialization in the areas they worked, I could effectively use a directive style with great success. These employees were ready to listen and follow all the directions that I gave them. On the contrast, this strategy did not work well with the highly trained professionals such as branch managers and line managers who worked under me. This group of people was sometimes very resistant to my directives, and they even challenged most of the ideas that I proposed. This created a kind of tension since I felt that they were not respecting my authority while they felt that they were being undermined as professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was, therefore, a need for a compromise if the outcome was to be improved. This experience taught me that the leadership style that should be adopted with people with professional training should be different from the style that is adopted when dealing with employees who have no professional training. This is because when a manager is dealing with non-professionals, he enjoys expert power, and this can make him have a more significant influence over them. However, when dealing with fellow professionals, the manager is at the same level as them since they all have similar training in their areas of expertise. As a result, all of them have equal authority as far as professionalism is concerned. The leader must understand that he is professionally at par with the other professionals with the only difference being that he has been entrusted to a position of leadership. Using directive styles such as autocratic leadership style may not work since these people have different professional views which may be better than those of the leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another lesson that I learned from my experience is that leadership styles should be based on the local culture. Some of the things that may be acceptable in one culture may be unacceptable in another culture. As a result, transferring leadership strategies that have worked in one culture and introducing them to a different culture can lead to disastrous results. Business must be seen to respect and adapt to the culture that exists in the environment where it operates. In doing so, both the employees and the general community will be in a position to embrace the business operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After learning through experience, there are things that I have done differently as opposed to how I did them. First, I would have considered the importance of involving employees, especially professionals, in the decision-making process. All professionals, irrespective of whether they are in a managerial position or not, are experts and hence they have authority in their areas of specialization. As such, these professionals must be treated as so, and they should be given an opportunity to make their contributions relating to how the organization should be run. For this group of employees, I would use the participative approach where all the professionals are given a chance to make contributions to the decision making process. This is very advantageous to the organization in that when employees are involved in the decision-making process; they are able to own up the decisions made. This acts as a motivation to them since they feel that they are party to the decisions made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In dealing with employees in a different culture, I would take a different approach than the one I took. I would first seek to learn and familiarize myself with the local culture before I can make any management decision. This can be achieved through the involvement of the employees who work in the different cultures who would act as a guide to making decisions that are compliant to the local culture. This would ensure that all the decisions that are made are acceptable in the local culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/leadership-people-system-self/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/leadership-people-system-self/</guid>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The essence of human capital impact on technological progress and economic growth</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological progress represents a development in technology that is greater than scientific understanding. In this case, technology comprises of all kinds of knowledge, from undemanding and routine processes to techniques of business and supervision, from apparatus primarily requiring several blue-collar employees, to sophisticated scientific inquiry which create innovations and goods. Technological progress is the centre of industrialization as well as economic growth. Numerous aspects are influencing the economic development including resource allocation, economies of scale and level of education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manufacturing sector lacks the necessary planning in scientific investigations and technical progress. In technological progress, many governments rely on external expertise rather than promoting the development of local human capital. Currently, the main achievement of technological development takes place due to thorough R&amp;amp;D done by private sectors and also governments. Momentous and continued attempts in R&amp;amp;D, together with the technical arrangement, are the significant components of technological progress and competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from generating information, investing in R&amp;amp;D can be the basis of developing technological ability that permits speedy acquisition and information dissemination. Macro-economic proof demonstrates that human capital contributes to economic development. Both social and fiscal proceeds of human capital are necessary, just like physical capital as such economic indexes integrate a series of information associated with abilities, training and level of education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human capital has been widely used to demonstrate the economic effect. Besides, human capital is used in technological development as a primary indicator to describe economic increase, making it an aspect that increases the efficiency of labour and balances capital growth simultaneously. However, technological development ought to be stable for a given phase of evaluation, excluding the likelihoods of increasing the rate of creativity or a realistic decreasing of creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economic theories increase the accumulation of human capital, leading to endogenous economic development models which adequately describe the association between economic increase and technological progress. Even though technological progress is mostly deployed for the aim of replacing labour aspect, there are exceptional complements of human capital, though its econometrically intricate to establish. The entertainment ability of technology makes it disapprovingly rebound in the increase of productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investments in R&amp;amp;D are related to innovations, though loosely since the quantity of investment never depicts the quality of creativity. Product brands evaluate the production of new products as well as services in the market, or changes in the marketing penetration strategies for old goods and hence demonstrates a more instant effect on output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, business innovation includes more than these indicators. Companies in Australia implementing improvement are probable to devote to acquiring new tools, marketing and training instead of investing in research and development. Studies on improvements in the United States, European Union and Japan reported that companies believe that patents are insignificant compare to other ways of appropriating their funds in improvement. Recognizing these aspects, the speed of creativity in developed economies indeed seems to reduce in 2000, although declines are not evident for the 80s or 90s. Copyright applications, brands and business-sponsored research and development in developed nations also reduced in the 2000s.
Nevertheless, in Australia, patents and business sponsored R&amp;amp;D continued to be more durable. This shows the impacts of product boom and stable income during that period. Primary as well as resource-based sectors cover a more significant percentage of business investment in R&amp;amp;D and are vital drives in the growth in recent times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It becomes imperative that human capital is an essential element of state-run economic competitiveness as indicated from a wide range of statistical reviews. What is apparent is that the more a nation develops, the more they need for human capital and technological advancement, to enhance competitiveness. For instance, more than twenty-four per cent of the 2007-2008 WEF competitiveness level of developed economies and more than sixteen per cent of the level of underdeveloped nations relate to human capital benchmarks. Modelling demonstrates that nations which are ranked highly can have a competitive edge, mainly when they carry our reforms that aim at enhancing human capital. However, these same nations should ensure they maintain and continue to upgrade their human capital and modern technology to remain competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effect of global novelty is not likely to be instantaneous, since for innovations to be rehabilitated to fabrication methods, which should be embraced by several businesses or persons to impact country output performance in a substantial way. Dwindling novelty is all about phases that witness both slow and fast growth globally leading to a development apex in the mid-twentieth century and a turn down ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is nevertheless argued that prospects lack for enhancing the pace which the global front line moves in the way that previous industrial renaissance has. However, the truth is that some of the probable explanations for synchronized economy productivity output turn downs consist a plummeting pace of innovation, the vanishing effect of breakthroughs in ICT and the disappearing effect of previous economic reforms and perhaps shifting production sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/essence-human-capital-impact-technological-progress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/leadership/essence-human-capital-impact-technological-progress/</guid>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
        <category>economics</category>
        
        <category>human capital</category>
        
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Consumers’ Attitude towards Branded Jewellery</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The times of economic crisis are hardly a favourable period for the luxury industry. However, sales levels that have been achieved by companies like Dior, Chanel, Yves Saint-Laurent, or Colbert are impressing. Understanding what makes people buy luxury goods even when the times of impulsive purchases have sunk into oblivion is very important, as it helps to ensure the sustainability of the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The present article approaches consumers’ attitudes toward branded jewellery across European markets. The objective of comparison across markets is to identify factors what influences buying decision of luxury goods. The article considers the identified factors to prove that sustainability of the industry is preconditioned by the fact that customers’ buying decision of luxury goods depends more on personal attitudes towards branded jewellery, rather than economic influences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although branded jewellery are an integral part of the market in both developed and developing countries, little research has been done to examine motivational values towards purchasing luxury branded products. This discrepancy can be explained by the lack of consensus on what goods should be viewed as luxurious. Experts at Deloitte review several approaches to identifying luxury goods. Goods that are viewed as luxurious have a specific set of attributes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some experts, for example, Yuan &amp;amp; Kumah consider goods to be luxury if they are within a specific price range. Another popular vision suggests that the exclusivity of their distribution characterizes luxury goods. To avoid possible confusion, this article adopts the definition of luxury goods that have been suggested by Vickers &amp;amp; Renand. In their article, experts note that “Luxury goods can be differentiated from normal or “non” luxury goods by the extent to which they exhibit a distinctive mix of three essential dimensions of instrumental performance in terms of functionalism, experientialism and symbolic interactionism”. The definition is plausible not only because it offers a set of criteria by which one can distinguish between luxury and non-luxury goods, but also suggests that a purchasing decision of luxury goods is mainly preconditioned by personal attitudes towards this type of goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A two-step survey of 440 French customers allows Dubois &amp;amp; Laurent come to several important conclusions regarding the perception of luxury goods. While approaching respondents’ attitude toward luxury goods, Dubois &amp;amp; Laurent conclude that customers associated luxury goods with such terms as “upscale”, “quality”, “good taste”, “class”, “flashiness”, and “bad taste”. The analysis of terms allows suggesting that many customers tend to experience ambivalent feelings when it comes to luxury products. The same person may view buying luxury items as an indicator of a good and a bad taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubois &amp;amp; Laurent further examines this ambivalence, who make assumptions why Europeans like or dislike luxury goods. The two most common reasons for which European consumers do not feel motivated to buy luxury products are lack of interest in luxury and a perceived lack of fit between the individual and luxury. The respondents who name the former reason do not see much value in luxury goods, so they do not have an appétit for them. In turn, respondents chose the second reason to explain their resilience to buying luxury goods by their inexpertise, uneasiness with luxury environments, or a feeling of artificiality when they wear luxury items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, respondents who demonstrate the “I like luxury” attitude view luxury goods as an area where they could advance their knowledge and a source of inspiration. They consider their aspiration to buy luxury goods as a contribution to a better life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are six factors that influence buying decisions of luxury goods in European consumers: high quality, price, scarcity, individualistic identity, superfluousness, and symbolism of luxury goods. Dubois &amp;amp; Laurent has identified high quality as a factor preconditioning buying decisions of luxury goods. While deciding to buy luxury goods, customers expect a superior worth and high level of brand availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very high price of luxury goods is perceived as a way to classify oneself as a social elite since luxury brands are often inaccessible to the significant chunk of society.
The scarcity of luxury goods shapes the perceived ability to differentiate from most other buyers. The more infrequent is the brand, the more worth customers perceive it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poly sensuality is another critical factor influencing the buying decision of luxury goods. For customers, choosing luxury brands is not only a way to realize materialistic expectations, but also an opportunity to experience aesthetic satisfaction, to discover another facet of one’s personality.
A common reason making customers consider buying luxury goods is to realize one’s sentiments. Luxury goods are often associated with quality validity and enduring values.
Superfluousness as a factor preconditioning buying decision of luxury goods “symbolizes the involvement possessing these brands expect concerning unique results rather that make use of the brands”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is thus evident that despite economic turmoil, the luxury industry continues its growth and development. It is attributed to the fact that the buying decision of luxury goods is preconditioned not only by economic, but also psychological factors. It can be concluded that the reasons for which customers choose to buy luxury products do not differ substantially from country to country. Customers consider buying luxury goods because the process is associated with a wide range of experiences, including perceived reliability, opportunity to classify oneself to a particular group of people, and unique aesthetic satisfaction. Although the perception of these and other discussed factors may change over time, the knowledge of them is fundamental. It provides insights into how the luxury industry resists economic turmoil and secures sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/luxury/consumers-attitude-towards-branded-jewelry/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/luxury/consumers-attitude-towards-branded-jewelry/</guid>
        
        <category>luxury</category>
        
        <category>consumers</category>
        
        <category>crisis management</category>
        
        
        <category>luxury</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Advanced Approaches to Management of Enterprise Activities</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectiveness of management system is typically determined by its compliance with the requirements of the internal and external environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my point of view, mass-market and relatively homogeneous consumer demand were inherent to the industrial age. Power of manufacturers in that period was accounted for unsaturated markets and limited choice available for consumers. In modern times, however, commodities are no longer in short supply. Still, there exists a lack of consumer demand related to the continuous increase in the number of manufacturers and to the maturity of markets. The transition of power from manufacturers to consumers was the result of this trend. When consumers have a choice, they tell the suppliers what goods they want to have as well as how, when, and how much they are ready to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transition of market power from manufacturers to consumers manifests itself also in the fact that expectations of consumers have sharply increased and competition in price and quality has become keener. Increasing competition presses to find the best ways to meet the demand and terminates the trend of broadening of choice logically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What’s measured improves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt; Peter F. Drucker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against this background, the reproduction process becomes significantly complicated and depends directly on the capability of an enterprise to satisfy the existing demand. There is a good reason that during less than half-century marketing has turned from sales function to real business philosophy. Currently, it may be said without exaggeration that marketing key decisions serve as the basis for the development of effective strategies of business growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, reproduction of economic system is possible only if products generated by the system are in demand on the market and are sold at the price which ensures defraying of costs and making of profit sufficient for motivating of business activities. Moreover, the higher the level of the earned profit is the greater opportunities for developing the system has. At the same time, the task of marketing as a management function is to search for the most advantageous for the economic system ways and conditions for complying with the requirements of the market, based on the available R&amp;amp;D and production potential, as well as to define the area of development of the latter in line with the forecasted changes of the market environment. Subject to marketing decisions, the most promising fields and types of activity are selected, and the areas of research and technological development of the system are identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peculiarities of the contemporary reproduction process establish asymmetry towards compliance with the requirements of the external environment, although the degree of asymmetry is not the same for different enterprises. The higher the values of parameters and the potentials are, the more considerable influence on the environment it has and the more actively it creates its factors in line with its interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in the general case, the success of business operations depends on how it can adjust itself to the impact of the external conditions: economic, research and technological, social and political. Competitions, markets, prices, interaction with other systems, risks and a number of other factors determine the current position of the economic system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Depending on the degree of impact, three types of management systems can be distinguished:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management in relatively quiet external environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management in dynamic external environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management in crisis situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management in reliance on control and management by intermediate results are the varieties of the management systems of the first type. Management by objectives, project management and management in reliance on anticipation of changes are peculiar to the management systems of the second type. Finally, management systems of the third type are based on management by weak signals and management in response to unexpected events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every type of management is characterized by peculiar features and implies a specific technology of making managerial decisions. For example, implementation of mechanistic (bureaucratic) organizational structures, the high degree of centralization of management activities, the existence of rules and standards of carrying out of such activities, strict procedures for control and management style oriented towards the established procedures are intrinsic to the management systems of the first type which have been widely practised at the industrial stage of economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management systems of the second type rely on the implementation of organic (adaptive) organizational structures, decentralization of management activities, intra-corporate democracy and creation of opportunities for reaching of the potential of employees to a greater extent.
Management systems of the third type will be characterized by building up of a network of quick response teams and special communication channels as well as by reallocation of management functions related to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selection of management type, as well as a selection of principle of enterprise design, is made, depending on such parameters as field and scope of activities, level of diversification and integration. In the context of the most dynamic and aggressive environment, preference is given to building up of enterprises based on lifecycle and the basis of programmed or tracing control. Application of the technology-based principle of building up of enterprises as well as extreme or adaptive types of management is customary for companies which operate in the environment characterized by limited instability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be easily noticed that enterprises built up under the principle of the technological chain are inherent to economic systems of industrial-type while building up of enterprises based on lifecycle is common for the postindustrial stage of economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long-held beliefs about principles and methods of ensuring of effective presence of enterprises on the market undergo significant changes in the globalized world. Globalization of business and increasing aggressiveness of the external environment contribute to further development of the potential capacity of enterprises and diversification of risks by means of developing new regions and fields of business activities. Furthermore, dealing with various types of products and on different markets has peculiar features, thus predetermining selection of product-specific and region-specific lines of activity and delegation of a part of management functions to managers responsible for the development of these lines of activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There emerges a necessity to disintegrate the management corps into managers who support operations of the corporate headquarters and managers of specific product-based and region-based lines of activity. However, corporation headquarters retain the essential functions, such as determining of development strategy, financial and personnel policy, accounting and analysis of results of operations and working out of incentive mechanisms. Functions the contents of which are determined by peculiar features of products (research and technology advancement of a product or technology system, preparation and management of business process, inventory and logistics management and primary accounting of results of operations) are delegated to the level of specific product-based lines of activity. It is within the scope of product-based lines of activity that R&amp;amp;D and manufacturing process is implemented, covering all stages of the product lifecycle from when the necessity emerges to the stage of operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days it is not enough to update business process in some way or another. The objective is to accomplish significant reconstruction of the entire system of business process and to achieve a real breakthrough in its development in compliance with new parameters of performance of the market-driven economy. New philosophy implies abandoning of traditional principles of organization and operation and customary pyramid hierarchy structures.  Nowadays production systems shall develop, based on the concept of re-integration of separate operations in unified business processes, i.e., in interconnected and consistent sets of operations (inclusive of management operations) creating an outcome which is of value for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/strategic-management/advanced-approaches-management-enterprise-activities/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/strategic-management/advanced-approaches-management-enterprise-activities/</guid>
        
        <category>strategic management</category>
        
        <category>approach</category>
        
        
        <category>strategic-management</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Methods of Brand Protection</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the article “&lt;a href=&quot;https://mgroh.eu/blog/brand-management/methods-risk-assessment-brand-management/&quot;&gt;Methods of Risk Assessment in Branding&lt;/a&gt;”, I described the methods of risk assessment. You have assessed the risks and now ask yourselves: But how can we protect our brand? And it is one of the most important questions nowadays. Having entered the market, a brand goes through different stages of its development, transforming the brand essence from a set of identifying elements to the value which is perceived by consumers as a set of functional and emotional elements making a whole with the product and the way of its representation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of formation of emotional attitude to a brand can also include the following phases: brand awareness, obtaining further information, respect, loyalty, brand confidence, friendship and long-term partnership. Therefore, when it comes to brands, it is necessary to speak about the existence of a notion of the brand lifecycle the phases of which include brand creation, the market launch of the brand, brand development and ageing of the brand. Nevertheless, this notion is absent in the majority of sources related to branding. Many existing brands start with one product and continue to grow, comprising a variety of products. Even though the ability to remain unchanged for an extended period is one of the essential characteristics of the brand, all brands experience a process of ageing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A brand for a company is like a reputation for a person. It’s hard to build and easy to lose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt; Maximilian Groh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the phases of development and maturity of brand constitute the main object of application of various techniques of brand protection, including as it relates to a maximum increase of time duration of the maturity period and preventing from transition to ageing and decay. Since it is during the third and the fourth phases that the profit rate is increasing, a problem of possible ambush marketing arises which is related to the technique of promotion of one’s products with the use of elements of someone else’s brand with high capitalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other part, a lifetime of the brand is not critical if within the minimum period such brand has carried out the mission with respect to the volume of sales. As can be seen from the above, the time frame within which the protective mechanisms of the brand shall be activated is rather inexplicit. From this perspective, it is necessary to mark out two approaches to brand protection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proactive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; approach includes methods which prevent unlawful use of brand before the finding of facts of such use and is mainly applied at the phases of creation and launch of the brand;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reactive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; approach implies employing of methods of response to already existing violations and using of elements of someone else's brand when promoting one's products and is mainly applied at the phase of brand maturity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Methods of brand protection can be considered in the context of the following aspects:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acquisition of control in the related areas;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limitation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diversification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acquisition of control in the related areas &lt;/em&gt;means, first of all, long-term planning of brand development. Even having the main characteristics, not every brand is successful. Thus, according to the statistics, the overwhelming majority of brands (more than 90%) exit from the market during the first 2-3 years of their existence. Managerial methods of brand protection shall be aimed at creation of such brand characteristics as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;general purposefulness: the brand is able to ensure competitive advantage irrespective of what the company is engaged in;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ability to arouse interest in itself: strong brands are able to give new birth to enterprises and sometimes even to branches of industry;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being under constant supervision: to maintain the strength of brands, it is necessary to work consistently with them; it enables us to avoid a limited lifecycle;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;formation of brand equity which is the added value with which he brand empowers its products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brand equity can be represented in various preferred actions or the following consumer responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greater readiness to try a product or a service;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;less time duration required for completing of a proposed deal;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;higher probability that a product or a service will be purchased;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readiness to buy products of this brand more often than other products of the same category;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readiness to pay the premium price;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lower sensitivity to increase in prices;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lower propensity to try competitors' offers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective brand management shall provide the possibility for the implementation of proactive strategies to maintain and accumulate of brand equity. Effective brand management shall rely on the analysis of the consequences of marketing decisions with respect to the development of the brand in future, include brand endorsement and search for new sources of capital. Maintaining and long-term development of the created brand includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making changes in brand perception;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;investments in brand development;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;variety of tactical approaches for supporting the strategies with respect to the priority lines of brand development;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recovery and promotion of the brand, including by means of returning to the initial positioning and values of the brand;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;entry of brand into new markets;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repositioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the real world of brand development, occupation of a position implies repositioning in most cases. As a rule, an operating company already has a definite position. It is necessary to understand in the majority of cases whether it is worthwhile to carry out repositioning. To make such a conclusion, it is necessary to figure out what the current position is like. When repositioning, the following principles shall be taken into consideration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repositioning is an integral part of brand development;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;brand should not be repositioned too often;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constant research and analysis of consumer needs and actions of competitors is required;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repositioning means costs associated with the creation of an image for the purpose of changing of perception;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all the products or services available in the channels of distribution shall be changed in line with the new repositioning;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maximization of efforts which can impact the brand perception;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to carry out repositioning, it is required to add value or to change the target audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Models of traditional marketing usually solve the problem of brand extension from the standpoint of mixing of different product categories and transfer of the positive image of the existing brand to some other product. Making decisions on new products and brand extension with the use of an empirical approach is predetermined by three factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the extent to which the new product and extension will be beneficial to the empirical image of the company or brand;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the extent to which the new product and extension will bring new emotions which can be intensified in additional new products and further brand extensions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the extent to which they will contribute to the creation of holistic emotions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long-term development of the brand also includes its differentiation related to the output of premium goods for making more significant profits. Differentiation of brand is connected with market segmentation, finding of target markets and the creation of brands for certain groups of consumers. Diversification of brand makes it possible to sell a wide range of products under one brand which enables the brand to survive in the environment of a rapidly changing consumer market. Diversification is directly related to the development of the concept of an umbrella brand. Companies should strive for endorsement of their brands and retain the market share, flavouring the brands with a particular emotional image. Expansion of influence of known and expensive brand enables a company to maintain interest in the brand as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, long-term development of brand should also include optimization of the brand portfolio for the purpose of identifying of such assets protection of which is complicated. Basic names which imply conventional product description (branding) pertain to such brands. It is generally accepted to use the best-known types of brand architecture – Branded House and House of Brands – for a description of the brand portfolio. In the first case, a single brand (master brand) is used for embracing of a line of offers introduced under sub-brands. In the second case, a group of individual brands is used, which exist independently and are oriented towards increasing the market share and maximizing of profits. Consumers build their relations with brands based on direct and indirect experience. That is why interaction between brands of the same portfolio can have a favourable or adverse impact on increasing of value both of a single brand and the entire portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When creating the brand portfolio, the key moment is to determine the principles of its creation. The standard architectures of portfolio are as follows: &lt;em&gt;by price levels (high, middle and low), by consumer choice and product features &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;by assortment groups.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far as the creation of new possibilities requires distribution of investments among many brands, it is necessary to focus on a balanced portfolio of brands rather than on individual brands. Not all brands make an equal contribution to the increase in the value of the brand portfolio. That is why it is necessary to assess the brands included in the portfolio with regard to compliance with the key possibilities and availability of potential for the creation of value. Such assessment enables to arrange brands in terms of their investment attractiveness.
&lt;em&gt;Limitation &lt;/em&gt;implies using methods of control of brand profitability and launching of pilot projects. Control of brand profitability can be exercised in three main directions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment of value of the brand itself;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment of brand impact on sales effectiveness;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment of brand impact on the value of the company shares.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method of discounted cash flows developed by Interbrand in 1989 is the best-known approach used for the assessment of brand value. Forecast of future cash inflows generated by the brand underlies this method. Its advantage is that the method of assessment of brand value by discounted cash flows is the mirror reflection of the method used by investors for a valuation of companies and thereby it associates a brand value with the value of company shares. Another approach to the assessment of brands proposed by The Boston Consulting Group involves a calculation of brand value by such indicators as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;increase in mark-up (consumers are ready to buy products at higher prices);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;increase in volumes of sales (volume of sales of branded products is higher than of that of similar unbranded products;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;brand expansion (brand gives additional value to other products).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assessment of brand impact on sales effectiveness enables to identify how great is the contribution of the brand to the current total successfulness of sales of a company and how steady it is. One can speak about quantitative change in the impact of the brand strength on sales of a company. In this case, analysis of the following indicators should be carried out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contribution of the brand to increase in profitability of product in relation to unit costs for brand endorsement;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contribution of the brand to increase in the volume of sales of these products in relation to the volume of sales of similar unbranded products through these channels of distribution;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;possibility of brand extension and extension of its target segment in the medium term; it enables to assess how much additional cash flows can increase from using of the brand in future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, control of brand profitability depends to a large extent on the chosen evaluation technique, price category to which the brand pertains and on the occupied market share. With respect to brands of the premium price category, transfer to the standard price category means, as a rule, decrease in profitability. That is why constant control is required with respect to the price category to which the product pertains, in the first place, from the standpoint of consumers. When exercising control and making decisions, it is advisable to establish a balance between the short-term indicators (price category of brand, amount of profit, etc.) and the long-term indicators of brand development (image, perception).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launching of pilot projects on validation of idea, concept and imagery of brand enables to assess the prospects for development and the possibilities of profit-making before the market launch of the brand. It should be taken into consideration that resources spent in this connection offer the possibility to obtain the respective experience, to adjust the identified shortcomings on a timely basis before the phase of market launch and to avoid financial losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diversification&lt;/em&gt; as one of the methods of managerial protection of brand involves control of the points of contact with customers and with a delegation of control of communications to the consumers. Points of contact with the brand (brand-touch points) shall be understood to mean all the means of interrelation between brand and consumers, employees and other interested persons of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, S. Davis and M. Dunn (Davis, Scott M., and Michael Dunn. &lt;em&gt;Building the brand-driven business: Operationalize your brand to drive profitable growth&lt;/em&gt;. San Francisco, CA, 2002.) propose to classify the points in four categories by different parameters of interrelation between brand and consumers: points of contact before making a purchase which influence the final decision of a customer to purchase a product; points of contact when making a purchase which facilitate the very purchasing of the product; points of influence which show up after the sale of the product, including its use and servicing; supportive points of contact which indirectly assist a brand in making of the appropriate impression on consumers and partners. It is characteristic that the brand-touch points of the first two types play a critical role with regard to achieving of the short-term objectives of brand development while the brand-touch points of the third and fourth types play a crucial role in relation to the long-term perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following priority points of contact can be distinguished analysis and control whereof appear to be the most important for the purpose of implementation of the methods of brand protection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Printed, outdoor, TV and radio advertising;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display in the points of sale;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using of web-site;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commercial partners who direct actions of consumers when making decisions on purchase;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support desk in the format of a call-center;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employees of the company, both currently employed and ex-employees;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyst who monitor operations of the company;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing customers of the company who come into play, among other things, and influence the process of making of decisions on purchase by other consumers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balanced use of human and brand resources should be brought into focus, thus ensuring the internal activity when implementing the measures of brand protection.
The said instruments and methods of brand protection are primarily based not only on the long-term planning of brand development and designing of brand strategy but also on exercising of constant control of brand profitability, contact of the brand with consumers, monitoring and optimization of brand portfolio and closer attention when carrying out of company reorganization. As can be seen from the above, constant monitoring of brand development and performance as well as carrying out of the procedure for brand audit are among the conditions of brand protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/brand-management/methods-brand-protection/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/brand-management/methods-brand-protection/</guid>
        
        <category>brand management</category>
        
        <category>brand protection</category>
        
        <category>methods</category>
        
        
        <category>brand-management</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strategic and Operations Management - Relevancy</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management of contemporary enterprises operating in dynamic and complicated external environment and increasingly depending on it shall be strategic.
The fundamental distinctions between operations management and strategic management (Table 1) come down to the following aspects.
With all the variety of approaches, one can distinguish certain characteristic features inherent to strategic management as a management technique and thereupon solve the issue of appropriateness and effectiveness of its using in the environment of a specific economic entity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Table 1. Fundamental Differences between Operations Management and Strategic Management&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table-bordered&quot;&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Characteristics&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Operations Management&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Strategic Management&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Mission, intended purpose&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;manufacturing of products and rendering of services for the purpose of generating of income from sales&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;survival of the organization in the long-term perspective by way of establishing of dynamic balance with the environment&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Focus of attention of management&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Insight into an organization, a search of ways of more efficient resource usage&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Outsight outwardly organization, a search of new opportunities in competition, tracking and adjustment to changes in the environment&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Consideration of time factor&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Orientation towards short-term and mid-term perspective&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Orientation towards long-term perspective&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Basis of the building of management system&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Functions and organizational structures, procedures, techniques and technologies&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;People, information system and market&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Approach to human resources management&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;View of employees as a  resource of the organization, as a performer of specific works and functions&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;View of employees as the framework of the organization, its core value and source of its welfare&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Criterion of management efficiency&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Profitability and rationality of use of business potential&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Timeliness and accuracy of the response of the organization to new market challenges and changes, depending on changes of the environment&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first peculiar feature and, at the same time, the advantage of strategic management is determined by the fact that, on the one hand, strategic management enables to widen the scope of management activity and to include not only the critical elements of the internal environment of the organization but also the external aspects of its operations in the system intended for making and implementation of managerial decisions.
On the other hand, long-term objectives of enterprise development cease to be a reflection of the environment of its current activity but turn out to be the result of analysis of the changes in the external and internal environment. Besides, strategic management creates conditions for the making of proactive decisions and interactive operating of the management system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another peculiar feature is that the effectiveness of using strategic management depends on several prerequisites, including the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;organization has a clear vision of what it intends to achieve in future;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;main sources of problems are concentrated outside the organization rather than inside;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;organization has implemented technology for timely detection of problems and means for solving of problems;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managerial response to risks and threats is proactive in nature;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; centre of influence in management is shifted towards anticipation and prevention of adverse development of situation or to the minimization of losses if the adverse scenario is inevitable;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;objectives and direction of development are selected, based on the use of opportunities to full advantage which are offered as a result of changes in the external environment;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential of the organization is the function of changes occurring in the external environment and is flexibly adjusted to the long-term objectives and tasks of development of the organization;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;daily management constitutes continuation and concretization of strategic management and is exercised within the scope of the existing strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should also be remembered that the basis of the development of strategies for business growth is made up of such components as potential and competitiveness. Irrespective of what concept is behind the development of strategic plans – MOS Concept (Mission, Objectives, Strategies) or a more advanced concept of core competencies and dynamic capabilities – it is assumed that alongside with weaknesses, the enterprise has both advantages and certain potential of growth. Enterprise can independently use these advantages for the achievement of the objectives in view, exchange them or use together with its partners within the scope of network-based conduct of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lack of conditions required for effective integration in the market system has put many European enterprises in complicated economic situation. If previously enterprises could find a guaranteed market, in the new environment (market conditions and its unpredictable development), sales of products are put in a position of dependency on compliance with the market requirements, i.e., on their competitiveness. In its turn, manufacturing of competitive products requires permanent renewal of products and technological systems as well as using of progressive forms of arrangement and management of the business process. But these tasks cannot be solved in the absence of required domestic savings and the possibility to raise funds available for investment from the third parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since under the current conditions enterprises can far from always earn the required funds by themselves and owners of funds available for investment consider investments in industrial production to be quite risky and unprofitable, the circle of problems is closed. Hence, one has to witness with increasing frequency of how enterprises become insolvent and subsequently bankrupt. That is why it is so relevant under the current conditions to find and implement such form and methods of management which could enable to recover businesses from the critical condition and, in case of bankruptcy, to prepare and implement turnaround programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the point at issue is not that enterprises shall completely abandon the strategic management in the new environment. Since only if proven strategies are available, enterprises can address the challenge of survival and development in future, build up a system of interconnected and consistent marketing, financial, research and development plans as well as create effective mechanisms for the achievement of their objectives. However, the management system shall be improved on a step-by-step basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgroh_eu&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxgroh/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; for updates and let me know if something can be improved in this article. If you like this article, please leave a like or a comment. Thank you for your support.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/strategic-management/strategic-anti-crisis-management-relevancy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/strategic-management/strategic-anti-crisis-management-relevancy/</guid>
        
        <category>strategic management</category>
        
        <category>operations management</category>
        
        <category>methods</category>
        
        
        <category>strategic-management</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
